# Lewis Stratton

44 Balmoral Circuit Blakeview SA 5114 Home: (08) 82542777 Mobile: 0405 321 874

Email: <a href="mailto:lewisstrat@gmail.com">lewisstrat@gmail.com</a>

#### EXECUTIVE SUMMARY

I am a highly motivated self-starter with a commitment to lifelong learning. My goal is to proactively contribute to the continuous improvement of self-insured work health and safety systems. Injury management experience has reinforced the importance of a proactive approach. My experience encompasses varied risk profiles, from office-based through to medical/technical and high risk operational work. I have designed and conducted internal WHSW audits and been the organisational liaison for WorkCover evaluations. I have extensive staff, financial, program and project management experience at a senior level in community and government settings.

#### CAREER SUMMARY

Department of Planning, Transport & Infrastructure	Principal HR Consultant (WHSW)	2011 - current
<b>Attorney-General's Department</b>	Principal HR Consultant (OHSW)	2005 - 2011
<b>Attorney-General's Department</b>	Principal Project Officer (Disability)	2005 (5 months)
<b>Attorney-General's Department</b>	Project Manager (Injury Management Shared Service)	2004 - 2005
Department of Education & Children's Services	District Coordinator Children's Services	1997 - 2004
Department of Education & Children's Services	Coordinator Preschool Programs	1999 - 2001
<b>Children's Services Office</b>	Regional Manager (Executive)	1996 (6 months)

#### EMPLOYMENT HISTORY

Department of Planning, Transport & Infrastructure (SA Govt)

2011-current
Principal HR Consultant (WHSW)

### **SCOPE**

I am a senior member of the corporate WHS&W team, actively contributing to policy and strategy review and implementation. On occasion, as required by the department, I have assumed the acting role of Manager Organisational Environment.

### Responsibilities

- WHSW Consultancy
- Communication and consultation with internal stakeholders
- Active contribution to
  - o System review, development and documentation
  - o Policy review and development

- o Development and implementation of audits and assessments
- o Development and implementation of training
- Executive Officer of the departmental WHSW Committee
- Departmental decision-maker with regard to Worker's Compensation Claim determinations

# **Achievements**

- Active role in implementing the Work Health & Safety Act 2012
- Development and implementation of hazard and incident reporting training
- Oversight of WHSW induction of new sections transitioning from other departments
- Development of strong relationships with stakeholders across the organisation
- Successfully supporting WHSW as A/Manager Organisational Environment

# **Attorney-General's Department (SA Govt)**

2005-2011

Principal HR Consultant (OHSW)

### **SCOPE**

I was responsible for all aspects of the Attorney-General's Department OHSW Management System and also responsible for liaison, coordination and reporting functions across the Justice Portfolio (i.e. SA Police, Department of Corrections, SA Fire & Emergency Services, Courts Administration Authority and Attorney-General's Department). I prepared, and on occasion copresented, quarterly OHSW and Injury Management reports to the Justice Portfolio Leadership Council (i.e. Commissioner for Police and Chief Executives of Justice Portfolio agencies).

# Responsibilities

- Lead responsibility for
  - o OHSW Consultancy
  - o Communication and consultation with internal and external stakeholders
  - o System review, development, documentation and reporting
  - o Development and implementation of audits and assessments
  - o Development and implementation of training
  - o Worker's Compensation Claim determinations
- Executive Officer of the departmental WHSW Committee

### Achievements

- Established the "Justice Framework" for the implementation of the SA Government "Safety in the Public Sector 2007 2010 Strategy"
- Development and implementation of "Workplace Safety in AGD", defining the organisation's OHSW programs.
- Implementation and day-to-day management of Service Level Agreement with worker's compensation claims and rehabilitation management service provider

Attorney-General's Department (SA Govt) Principal Project Officer (Disability) 2005

### **SCOPE**

I undertook this short term role to develop the department's draft Disability Action Plan as part of the SA Government's "*Promoting Independence Strategy*". The draft plan became the basis for wider consultation.

### Responsibilities

- Establishment of, and engagement with the Disability Action Plan reference group
- Generalist HR functions as required

### **Achievements**

• Completion of the Attorney-General's Department draft Disability Action Plan

### **Attorney-General's Department (SA Govt)**

2004-2005

Project Manager Injury Management Shared Service

#### **SCOPE**

Reporting to the Director HR, I was responsible for managing the Injury Management Shared Service project, across the Justice Portfolio, with the aim of ensuring consistent and high quality injury management services across the portfolio.

# Responsibilities

- Managing and monitoring project timelines
- Managing staff with regard to HR transition strategies
- Analysis of cost benefits
- Regular liaison with and reporting to the reference group of Directors and Managers, HR
- Development and refinement of viable project proposals

#### **Achievements**

- Developed a range of "shared services" options, including Service Level Agreements and Job Descriptions
- Oversaw the research, development and publication of internal Justice papers on areas of high injury risk, contributing to reduced worker's compensation liabilities

# Department of Education & Children's Services (SA Govt) District Coordinator Children's Services

1997-2004

# **SCOPE**

I was responsible for the effective provision and/or support of early childhood services within a district entailing implementation of major DECS strategic priorities.

### Responsibilities

- Implementation of departmental strategic and curriculum priorities
- Program and staff management responsibilities across preschools, Family Day Care, centre
  based child care, playgroups, play centres, early learning programs, out of school hours care
  and occasional care services.

### **Achievements**

- Establishment of several new children's centres
- Leadership contribution to the implementation of curriculum frameworks and initiatives

# Department of Education & Children's Services (SA Govt) Coordinator Preschool Programs

1999-2001

#### **SCOPE**

I had state-wide responsibility for resource allocation to 400 preschools and policy development role with regard to the full range of children's services across the state.

# Responsibilities

- Monitoring utilisation / attendance trends and allocating staff and financial resources to state government preschools
- Policy development across the full range of children's services

#### **Achievements**

- Development of the preschool staffing model, implemented as part of the *Partnerships 21* initiative
- Development of a computer based monthly reporting system for Occasional Child Care Services (in commission for over 20 years).
- Effective management of a \$40m preschool staffing budget

# **Children's Services Office**

1996 (6 months)

Regional Manager, North East Region (Executive role)

### **SCOPE**

I managed a large regional multi-disciplinary team, providing support and services to the full range of children's services in one of three Children's Services Office regions.

### Responsibilities

- Management of a large multi-disciplinary regional team (social workers, aboriginal community workers, speech therapists, special education teachers, regional coordinators etc.)
- Management of a \$20m regional budget
- Oversight of the regional transition of the Children's Services Office to the Education Department of SA

#### **Achievements**

• Successful regional transition of the Children's Services Office to the Education Department

### EDUCATION/QUALIFICATIONS

Certificate IV in Programming
Certificate IV in Training & Assessment

Commenced 2013
Commenced 2013

(TAFE SA, Adelaide)

Advocacy Skills for HR Practitioners & Managers

2008

(University of Adelaide)

**Advanced Diploma in Government: Occupational Health & Safety** (MARC South Australia) **2007** 

Page 4 of 5

# **Bachelor of Arts: (Psychology & English)**

(Flinders University South Australia)

1982

# GENERAL TRAINING AND DEVELOPMENT

# **Internal OHSW Auditing**

2007

(WorkCover SA – Trainer: Glenn Fox)

# Apply advanced first aid (HLTFA402C)

2012

(O.R.C.A. - Ocean Recreation Careers Australasia)

### OTHER INTERESTS

- Scuba diving (Master Diver and other advanced qualifications)
- Kayaking
- Programming and website development
- Share market investing

#### REFEREES

# Ms Frankie Anderson General Manager Customer Services

Public Trustee Phone: 8226 9260 Mobile: 0401 122 468

E: frankie.anderson@sa.gov.au

# Ms Andrea Sax EPAS HR Manager

Health and Ageing (SA Health)

Phone: 7425 3155 Mob: 0410 006 246

E: Andrea.Sax@sa.gov.au

# Mr Peter Von Der Borch Principal Policy Consultant

Department of Planning, Transport & Infrastructure

Phone: 8226 2919

E: Peter.VonderBorch@sa.gov.au

# Mr Tim Reeves HR Consultant

Public Trustee Phone: 8226 9294

E: tim.reeves@sa.gov.au